Guide to the Harold K. Baumgardner menu collection, [ca. 1949-1965].
Baumgardner, Harold K. menu collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harold K. Baumgardner menu collection, [ca. 1949-1965].
8404
Baumgardner, Harold K.,
.8 cubic feet.
Printed material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
227 restaurant menus, collected by Baumgardner, 1940s-1960s.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
227 restaurant menus, collected by Baumgardner, 1940s-1960s. This collection consists of menus from across the United States and includes restaurants such as the Cliff House, the Blue Fox, and Julius Castle in San Francisco; The Original Don the Beach Comber in Hawaii, the Stock Yarn Inn in Chicago; The Men's Bar at the Waldorf Astoria in New York. It also includes hotel, airline and train menus and international menus from several countries in the Caribbean as well as from Mexico. The collection also contains some photographs and post cards relating to the restaurants. Many of the menus are dated by Baumgarnter and exhibit mid-20th Century graphic design elements, particularly some interesting 1950s genre fonts and motifs. Some menus from the South contain African American and racial elements.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Baumgardner, Harold K.,
Subjects:
Gastronomy.; Dinners and dining.; Restaurants.; Menus -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Menus -- Puerto Rico -- History -- 20th Century; Menus -- Canada -- History -- 20th Century; Menus -- Bahamas -- History -- 20th Century; Menus -- Jamaica -- History -- 20th Century; Menus -- Virgin Islands -- History -- 20th Century; Menus -- Mexico -- History -- 20th Century; Graphic Art -- 20th Century
Form and Genre Terms:
Menus.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. US East and US South, 1950-1965
  - US East: Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, May 28, 1951-November 13, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - US East: New York, March 8, 1950-October 28, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Mainly New York City
  - US East: Pennsylvania, Vermont, October 22, 1050-August 24, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - US South: Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, February 27, 1951-March 6, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - US South: Louisiana, Mississippi, March 3, 1952-November 28, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - US South: North Carolina, South Carolina, Virginia and West Virginia, October 21, 1950-August 7, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II. US Midwest, US West and US Airline and Train, 1949-1964
  - US West: Arizona, California, Hawaii, New Mexico and Texas., July 1949-April 4, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes US Airline and Train Menus
  - US Midwest: Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Missouri, August 6, 1949-July 15, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Menus from Illinois are mainly from Chicago
  - US Midwest: Ohio, Oklahoma, August 6, 1949-March 18, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series III. International and Unknown Locations, 1950-1957
  - International: Bahamas, Canada, Germany, Haiti, Jamaica, Mexico, Puerto Rico, Virgin Islands, March 5, 1951-March 14, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Unknown Locations, April 18, 1950-October 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Includes menu in the shape of a steak